<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Lynn Noda</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/feeds/blog.xml</id><subtitle>Recent Updates</subtitle><updated>2024-04-09T23:14:39Z</updated><link href="nodalynn.com/feeds/blog.xml" rel="self" /><link href="nodalynn.com" /><entry><title>Olympiad Solutions are Up!</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/olympiad-solutions-are-up.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2024-02-27T11:50:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/olympiad-solutions-are-up.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Math Updates&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;New Content&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After some months of working on new problems and doing write-ups (both on paper
and digitally), I present you the &lt;a href=&quot;/math/oly&quot;&gt;Olympiad corner&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before you dive in, be sure to read through &lt;a href=&quot;/math#olympiad&quot;&gt;this section&lt;/a&gt; on
my math page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The initial batch of problems range across the four areas (A, C, N, G) pretty
evenly, with some problems coming from multiple areas. There are twenty-five
problems in total, and the difficulty is on the easier side compared to harder
Olympiads. The selection consists of problems I've solved which I found
interesting, cute, instructional, prototypical, and/or anything in between.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I plan for this list to grow over time. Hopefully, as I gain more experience,
the difficulty and diversity of the problems will also broaden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I do not have geometry diagrams yet, so you'll have to make do
without them for now... sorry :(&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Math Tech... more like Math TeX!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://katex.org/&quot;&gt;KaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for math rendering. The syntax
is pretty much the same as LaTeX and it &lt;em&gt;just works&lt;/em&gt;. The nice thing about
KaTeX is that it adheres to the single responsibility principle: it only
renders math. The mess of formatting then becomes the responsibility of the
client. This sounds burdensome, but this also means that the client gets full
control over the page layout. You may miss theorem numbering and proof
environments, but that comes with it the hidden assumption that the document is
static. The dynamic web, on the other hand, has a whole host of tools that
allows you to present math in unconventional ways. KaTeX gives you that freedom
by getting out of your way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Olympiad solutions, my write-ups are stored and organized using a tool
called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vEnhance/von&quot;&gt;VON&lt;/a&gt;. It maintains modular chunks of
math that I can freely cut and paste wherever I want. This gives me a single
source of truth for any math I write digitally. Want to add a problem to an
article or book? Go to the source and add &lt;code&gt;\voninclude{PROBLEM_SOURCE}&lt;/code&gt;. Want
to retrieve a problem statement for an app or site?  Run a subprocess with&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;von show &amp;quot;PROBLEM_SOURCE&amp;quot; -b 0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, all I need to do is update VON, and the changes become reflected
everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my build process, I have a simple shell script that pulls Olympiad data
from VON, converts LaTeX to KaTeX readable&lt;label for=&quot;sn-485914-636983&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-485914-636983&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;The syntax that KaTeX expects is a bit different from traditional TeX/LaTeX (no dollar signs, environments wrapped in display mode), but good ol' PCRE's got my back.&lt;/span&gt; form,
and writes the output to temporary files. This is then read by my static site
generator to be integrated with anything added through markdown (including
custom extensions).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nice-To-Haves and Things-To-Fix&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the major update, before I forget, I'll mention a few minor things I
want add or fix for the site. This may or may not happen any time soon...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add a custom 404 page&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fix the URL slugs for the generated Atom feeds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make the ID/URL generation for image galleries consistent across builds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Add syntax highlighting for code blocks?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nano Life Updates/Plans&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I decided to order a programmable mechanical keyboard, and
now that I have it, I feel a lot faster compared to when I was only using my
laptop keyboard. This is especially true after having done twenty-five
write-ups.  &lt;label for=&quot;sn-416442-191775&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-416442-191775&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Although this may just be placebo...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides that, for the next few months, I'll probably get back into software. I
have things I want to hack for Zedigo(改). If things go well, maybe an MVP will
be on the horizon?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Binging Euclidean Geometry</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/binging-euclidean-geometry.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2023-12-23T04:46:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/binging-euclidean-geometry.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Euclidean Geometry is Underrated&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how cyclic quadrilaterals, radical axes, and homothety
have gradually taken over my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After publishing the initial site, I decided to take a break from code to do
something else for a while. At first I was considering drawing sketches or
solving combinatorics problems, but strangely enough, I found myself picking up
a geometry book I bought some years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've read my math page, you'll know that I enjoy discrete math, so it was
quite odd for me to suddenly crave for geometry. Perhaps the appeal was the
pretty diagrams I got to draw with compass and straightedge. I admit, there is
a certain meditative quality in patiently turning words into pictures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I made my way through the book and got acquainted with propositions,
theorems, and lemmas as I worked them out on sheets of paper. Eventually I
started solving some exercises, and soon I was craving to get past the theory
to dive right into the wild west of exhilarating problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One fun problem&lt;label for=&quot;sn-365675-232818&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-365675-232818&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;For those impatiently curious, the solution is on this site.&lt;/span&gt; I was immediately confronted with was the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;oly&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let \(C\) be a circle and \(P\) a given point in the plane. Each line
through \(P\) which intersects \(C\) determines a chord of \(C\). Show that the
midpoints of these chords lie on a circle.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Euclidean geometry lies in its simple character. There are no
crazy equations&lt;label for=&quot;sn-130389-275721&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-130389-275721&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;With the exceptions of rectilinear coordinates, complex numbers, barycentric coordinates, linear algebra, etc.&lt;/span&gt;, no confusing
objects, no fancy notation, yet results are often astonishing. It's no wonder
that geometry is called the &lt;strong&gt;king&lt;/strong&gt; of mathematics. And strangely, the process
of exploring and solving problems synthetically can often feel close to
discrete math.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, geometry gets a bad rap in conventional education and other
academic institutions. It's often written off as &amp;quot;useless&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;trivial&amp;quot; by
many. In fact, Euclidean geometry is a dead topic among &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; professional
mathematicians despite its historical origins. In a way though, the field is a
hidden gem—detached from the world, only showing itself to those who seek it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often hard as a beginner to recognize the depth to which something simple
manifests. When I tried getting into geometry years ago, the theory seemed too
&amp;quot;fundamental&amp;quot; and the problems too &amp;quot;similar&amp;quot;. Only now do I appreciate the true
depth that this humble subject has to offer. This is especially true after
solving many beautifully crafted Olympiad problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, now that I have pages filled with diagrams of problems and solutions,
it only worsens my ever-increasing queue of &amp;quot;math to convert to LaTeX&amp;quot;.
Diagrams are also more tedious because it requires additional tools like
Asymptote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, geometry has a new place in my heart. Gone are the days of &lt;em&gt;just
another find the length problem&lt;/em&gt;. It's a field where more of its magic is
revealed to you the deeper you go. But go too far, and you'll start looking for
concyclic points in stars and raindrops.&lt;label for=&quot;sn-492504-167721&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-492504-167721&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;This is the famous Tetris effect. My record is having diagrams appear in my dream. Besides geometry and Tetris, I've also dreamt of Lisp code.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's pretty much what I've been up to lately. Excuse my bad writing, this is
being written at 4 AM in the morning (revised a day later). ;p&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>First post!</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/first-post.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2023-12-07T01:32:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/first-post.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Hello world!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post. :D&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will likely post something here when significant changes to the site are
made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to subscribe to this blog's Atom feed or the feed for the whole site.
That way, you will be notified when there are new updates. If you don't know
how to subscribe to syndication feeds, just search for 'RSS/Atom Readers' on
your favorite search engine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a good day! ... or night if you're a nocturnal creature like me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>