<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Lynn Noda</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/feeds/feed.xml</id><subtitle>Recent Posts</subtitle><updated>2023-12-24T01:39:40Z</updated><link href="nodalynn.com/feeds/feed.xml" rel="self" /><link href="nodalynn.com" /><entry><title>Binging Euclidean Geometry</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/binging-euclidean-geometry.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2023-12-23T04:46:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/binging-euclidean-geometry.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Euclidean Geometry is Underrated&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how cyclic quadrilaterals, radical axes, and homothety
have gradually taken over my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After publishing the initial site, I decided to take a break from code to do
something else for a while. At first I was considering drawing sketches or
solving combinatorics problems, but strangely enough, I found myself picking up
a geometry book I bought some years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you've read my math page, you'll know that I enjoy discrete math, so it was
quite odd for me to suddenly crave for geometry. Perhaps the appeal was the
pretty diagrams I got to draw with compass and straightedge. I admit, there is
a certain meditative quality in patiently turning words into pictures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I slowly made way through the book, propositions, theorems, and lemmas flew
onto sheets of paper. And as I got acquainted with these objects, I started
solving some exercises. Soon I was craving to get past the theory to dive
straight into the wild west of exhilarating problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One fun problem&lt;code&gt;(sidenote &amp;quot;The solution can be found elsewhere. If motivation permits, I will post the solution on this site.&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt; I was immediately confronted
with was the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given a circle and a point inside of it, take all the chords through the point
and aggregate their midpoints. Prove that the resulting figure is a circle with
its diameter defined between the point and the center of the circle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Euclidean geometry lies in its simple character. There are no
crazy equations&lt;code&gt;(sidenote &amp;quot;With the exceptions of rectilinear coordinates, complex numbers, barycentric coordinates, linear algebra, etc.&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;, no confusing
objects, no fancy notation, yet results are often astonishing. It's no wonder
that geometry is called the &lt;strong&gt;king&lt;/strong&gt; of mathematics. I guess in this sense,
it's closer to the elegance of discrete math than it is to, say, algebra or
analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, geometry gets a bad rap in conventional education and other
academic institutions. It's often written off as &amp;quot;useless&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;trivial&amp;quot; by
many. In fact, Euclidean geometry is a dead topic among professional
mathematicians despite its historical origins. In a way though, the field is a
hidden gem—detached from the world, only showing itself to those who seek it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's often hard as a beginner to recognize the depth to which something simple
manifests. When I tried getting into geometry years ago, the theory seemed too
&amp;quot;fundamental&amp;quot; and the problems too &amp;quot;similar&amp;quot;. Only now do I appreciate the true
depth that this humble subject has to offer. This is especially true after
solving many beautifully crafted Olympiad problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, now that I have pages filled with diagrams of problems and solutions,
it only worsens my ever-increasing queue of &amp;quot;math to convert to LaTeX&amp;quot;.
Diagrams are also more tedious because it requires additional tools like
Asymptote.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, geometry has a new place in my heart. Gone are the days of &lt;em&gt;yet
another find the length problem&lt;/em&gt;. It's a field where more of its magic is
revealed to you the deeper you go. But go too far, and you'll start looking for
concyclic points in stars and raindrops.&lt;code&gt;(sidenote &amp;quot;This is the famous Tetris effect. My record is having diagrams appear in my dream. Besides geometry and Tetris, I've also dreamt of Lisp code.&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's pretty much what I've been up to lately. Excuse my bad writing, this is
being written at 4 AM in the morning (revised a day later). ;p&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Placeholder Essay</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/placeholder-essay.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2023-12-07T01:45:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/placeholder-essay.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Note: This is a placeholder essay!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although I've written quite a lot over the past years, I haven't really had the
time and energy to consolidate them into discrete chunks of publishable text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I decide to dig into my repository of writing anytime soon, you will likely
start seeing stuff appear here.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>First post!</title><id>https://nodalynn.com/first-post.html</id><author><name></name></author><updated>2023-12-07T01:32:00Z</updated><link href="https://nodalynn.com/first-post.html" rel="alternate" /><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Hello world!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post. :D&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will likely post something here when significant changes to the site are
made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to subscribe to this blog's Atom feed or the feed for the whole site.
That way, you will be notified when there are new updates. If you don't know
how to subscribe to syndication feeds, just search for 'RSS/Atom Readers' on
your favorite search engine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a good day! ... or night if you're a nocturnal creature like me.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>